(改编自乔治RR马丁小说 “血火同源”)
龙族前传
第三季第一集
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
冷静
跪下
Kneel.
我可以给你个痛快 或是...
I can make it clean, or...
至少让我知道我的罪名吧 王子殿下
Might I at least know the accusation, my prince?
告诉我他在哪里
Where is he?
- 谁  - 我哥哥 国王
- Who? - My brother, the king.
在他的寝宫
In his quarters!
你是王室的叛徒
You are a traitor to the crown.
- 我判你死刑 - 不
- I sentence you to die. - No!
王子殿下
My prince.
看来拉里斯大人也逃离了红堡
It appears Lord Larys has fled the Keep as well.
我需要罂粟花奶
I need milk of the poppy.
我们匆忙逃走 无暇顾及
I'm afraid in our hasty flight that I neglected to bring any.
好痛
Ah, the pain!
拜托
Please.
振作起来 国王陛下
Take heart, my king.
现在是黑暗的时刻 但是...
These are dark hours, but...
好日子就在眼前了
brighter days lie ahead.
不
No.
我是一无所有之王
I'm the king of nothing.
以渡鸦粪便为王座
With raven shit for a throne
瘸子为守护者
and a cripple for a protector.
我真可悲
Oh, I'm fucking pathetic.
该死
Oh, fuck!
把兜帽拉上
Draw your hood.
趴下
待在原地
等等...拜托帮忙一下
Wait, no, wait!
你们是什么人
Who are you?
为学城效力的普通百姓
Simple men in service of the Citadel.
我们要把这些渡鸦送去白港
We're taking these ravens to White Harbor.
你们身处女王的疆土
You're in the queen's lands.
若想由此通过 必须先谴责篡位者
If you mean to pass, you first have to denounce the usurper,
屈膝下跪 向女王陛下宣誓效忠
bend the knee. You swear fealty to Her Grace,
唯一真王 雷妮拉坦格利安
the one true queen, Rhaenyra Targaryen.
我们谴责篡位者
We denounce the usurper
并向雷妮拉坦格利安陛下宣誓效忠
and swear to Her Grace, Rhaenyra Targaryen.
来吧 朋友
Come on, friend.
宣誓你的效忠 我们才能继续赶路
Affirm your fealty so we might be on our way.
队长要你跪下
The captain said kneel.
去你的
Fuck you.
请原谅我的朋友 他有点不知变通
Forgive my friend, he can be so stubborn.
他们是伊耿的人
They're for Aegon.
将他们就地正法
Put them to the sword.
- 不 饶了我... - 大人 你今天走运了
- Wait, please. Please. - It's a very lucky day for you, my lord.
此人不愿宣誓效忠雷妮拉
The reason this man won't swear fealty to Rhaenyra...
是因为他就是伊耿坦格利安
is because he is Aegon Targaryen.
什么
What?
不是...那太...
No, no, that's--
朋友 你在玩什么把戏
What are you playing at, friend?
他就是爱开玩笑
Always jesting.
- 他说的是实话吗  - 不是...
- That true? - No.
当然不是 这根本是无稽之谈
No, of course not. These are lies.
他在鸦栖堡战役中
He was lustrated in dragonfire
被雷妮丝坦格利安 与她的龙用龙焰洗礼
by Rhaenys Targaryen... and her dragon at the Battle of Rook's Rest.
- 我的同伴很擅长编故事娱乐... - 我是效忠陛下的臣子
- My companion is always the gifted mummer. - I am His Grace's loyal councillor...
- 赫伦堡的领主 拉里斯斯壮 - 睁眼说瞎话
- ...and the Lord of Harrenhal-- - Outrageous fucking lies!
你们两个之中有人说谎
Someone's lying.
- 这是他的王冠 - 不是
- His crown. - No.
头发很漂亮
Pretty hair.
砍下他们的脑袋
Take their heads.
这能跟女王换取丰厚的赏金
We'll make a rich bounty for the queen.
- 请大人恕罪 但要是走错这一步 - 不...饶了我
- Forgive me, my lord... - No, no, no, please.
你连自己的脑袋都保不住
...but you would lose your own head for such a misstep.
这就是挑战者本人
This is the challenger himself.
只要将他和最受他信任的心腹
You can name your price for delivering him...
以俘虏的身分交给女王
and his most trusted confidant to the queen
价码随你开
as living hostages.
那他们又是什么身分
Who are they, then?
无关紧要的人
No one of consequence.
- 最近的港口在哪里  - 暮谷镇
- What's the nearest port? - Duskendale.
把他们关好 带过去
Bar them within. We'll take them there.
雇一艘船去龙石岛
And hire a ship to Dragonstone.
我很想相信
I have to believe...
阿莉森是真心想谈和
that Alicent's offer was genuine.
这只是打着过去友谊旗帜的诡计
It is a ruse cloaked in stale friendship.
她来这里无疑冒了很大的风险
The risk she took in coming here is beyond question.
那她现在要你冒的风险呢
And the risk she now asks you to take?
光凭她的片面之词 就飞去绿党的要塞
To fly to the Greens' stronghold based on her word alone.
这是个陷阱 母亲
It is a trap, Mother...
引诱你和戴蒙 进入瓦格哈尔的血盆大口
to lure you and Daemon into Vhagar's jaws.
不 瓦格哈尔和伊蒙德不在 他们飞去赫伦堡了
No! Vhagar and Aemond are gone. They have flown to Harrenhal.
而伊耿卧病在床
And Aegon is bedridden.
我可以一举拿下伊耿和王位
I could take both Aegon and the throne in a single stroke.
不
No.
你不能相信她
You cannot trust her.
母亲
Mother.
阿莉森来到龙石岛了
Alicent came to Dragonstone.
阿莉森
Alicent?
打着和平的旗帜
Under a banner of peace.
这怎么可能
Surely, this is not possible.
绿党明白他们的战败已成定局
The Greens know already that their defeat is written.
伊蒙德乘着瓦格哈尔 飞往河间地与科尔会合
Aemond flies on Vhagar to join Cole in the Riverlands.
他离开后 阿莉森就会打开红堡
With him gone, Alicent will open the gates of the Red Keep
把伊耿交给我处置
and surrender Aegon to me.
我会取下他的首级与王位
I will then take his head and the throne.
她提出什么条件 女王陛下
What are her terms, Your Grace?
饶她 海伦娜和杰赫妮拉一命
That she, Helaena, and Jaehaera are spared,
在不造成更多伤亡的情况下 结束这场战争
and that this war ends without further bloodshed.
这个代价微不足道
That is a low price.
你认为她值得信任吗
Do you believe she can be trusted?
传话给在喉道的科利斯大人
Get word to Lord Corlys in the Gullet.
我需要船只运送足够的兵力 来拿下那座城市
I require ships to deliver fighting men enough to secure the city.
- 女王陛下 我强烈抗议此举... - 戴蒙必须尽快回来
- Your Grace, I protest this action with all my po-- - And Daemon must return with haste.
我会写信给他
I'll write to him.
我们两天后飞往君临
We'll fly to King's Landing in two days' time...
拿下那座城市
and take the city.
早安 爵士
Good morrow, ser.
皇后 国王要召见你
My queen. The king requires an audience.
请移驾至王座厅 陛下
Rather to the throne room, Your Grace.
伊蒙德
Aemond.
你怎么会在这里
Why are you here?
伊耿已经退位了
Aegon has abdicated the throne.
退位 什么意思
Abdicated? What do you mean?
跟癞蛤蟆拉里斯一起逃离君临了
Fled King's Landing with that toad Larys.
不对 伊耿卧病在床
No, Aegon was bedridden.
他还能去哪里 为什么要这么做
Where could he have gone? Why?
因为他不仅是个懦夫 还很愚蠢
Because he's even more stupid than he is craven.
我们得派出搜索队 必须马上找到他
We must send a search party. He needs to be found immediately.
你去哪了 母亲
Where were you, Mother?
你好几天没出现在红堡了
You've not been seen in the Keep in days.
我去了御林 伊蒙德
I was in the Kingswood, Aemond.
我最近发现自己在这里没什么用处
I have found myself of little use here of late.
那赫伦堡呢
And what of Harrenhal?
你和瓦格哈尔 本该飞去见克里斯顿爵士
You and Vhagar were meant to fly to meet Ser Criston
协力挑战戴蒙
and challenge Daemon together.
伊耿让我别无选择 只能留在这里保卫这座城市
Aegon has left me no choice but to remain here and defend the city.
但援军就要来了
But aid is coming.
欧尔蒙大人和海塔尔家的 一万五千名士兵
Lord Ormund and 15,000 Hightower men
此刻正与戴伦和他的龙 一起沿着曼德河而上
presently march up the Mander with Daeron and his dragon.
三女儿王国的舰队随时会突袭封锁
And the Triarchy fleet will, at any moment,
他们的兵力是海蛇的三倍
ambush the blockade with a force thrice the Sea Snake's strength.
我们只需要等待时机
We only need to bide our time.
兰尼斯特的大军已被击溃 王子殿下
The Lannister host has scattered, my prince.
先锋部队被打散 后卫部队四分五裂 落荒而逃
The vanguard was smashed and the rearguard broken and fled.
金光闪闪的兰尼斯特大人呢
And what of the golden Lord Lannister?
当骑兵阵型溃散时 他就逃跑了
Fled when the cavalry broke rank.
我们的斥侯推测 他们会在诸神之眼附近重新集结
Our scouts believe they may be regrouping near the God's Eye.
那我们就在那里继续战斗 我们必须把他们赶尽杀绝
Then we'll continue the fight there. We must pursue them till the last.
- 为死者挖好坟墓 - 是 大人
- Have graves dug for our dead. - Aye, my lord.
科拉克休会迅速处理掉这些尸体
Caraxes would make short work of these bodies.
烧掉就不会引发瘟疫
And burnt flesh carries no plague.
那不是我们的传统
That is not our way.
河间地的子民必须入土为安
Rivermen must be returned to the mud.
大人
My lord!
- 全体备战 - 全体备战
To arms!
向我集结
Form on me!
我们来此为龙之女王效忠赴死
We have come to die for the dragon queen.
很好
Very good.
我们还有很多狮子要猎
We've got more lions to hunt.
早安 首相大人
Good morrow, Lord Hand.
有伊蒙德王子的消息吗
Has there been word from Prince Aemond?
没有 目前还没有
None. As yet.
他和瓦格哈尔 本该在鹿角堡和我们会合的
He and Vhagar were supposed to have joined us back at the Antlers.
我们毫无防备地行军
We march ever exposed.
- 如果他不来... - 他非来不可
- If he does not come-- - He has to come.
还有一件事
There is another matter.
我们的人蹂躏了一个村女
One of our men has ravaged a village girl.
我亲眼目睹此暴行
I witnessed the events myself.
必须有所处置
Something must be done.
你要的话可以吊死他
Hang him then, if you wish.
我不是总队长
I am not his Lord Commander.
惩罚的确势在必行
A punishment is due, yes,
但我们也必须向弟兄表明
but also a statement to the men.
我们不是野兽 而是拥有荣誉的骑士与士兵
That we are not beasts, but knights, and soldiers of honor.
看看你的四周 加尔温爵士
Look around you, Ser Gwayne.
看看天空
Look to the sky.
看看地平线
To the horizon.
末日与毁灭已将我们包围
Doom and ruin surround us.
在走向终结之前 我们都将沦为野兽
We will all become beasts before our end.
除非我们抛弃自己的原则
Only if we abandon our principles.
我从没见过我母亲
Never knew my mother.
和大部分贫民窟的贱民一样
Same as most of the gutter-rats.
活得比杂种狗还不如 天天被人踹
Was kicked about more than a mongrel dog.
我渴望死亡的日子 远比求生的念头来得多
Wished for death more days than I wished to live.
但有个来自埃索斯的红袍僧
There was this priest from Essos.
他对我有意思
He fancied me.
付我钱
Paid me coin.
要我做些事
To do things.
他说我身上流有国王的血脉
He said I had king's blood.
说我生来就肩负使命
That I was born for a purpose.
我喜欢那个故事
I liked that story.
所以我欣然接受了
So I owned it.
龙种乌尔夫
Ulf the Dragonseed.
结果那个红婊子没说错
And that red cunt was right.
你呢
And you?
你身上的龙之血脉是哪来的
Where'd you get your dragon's blood?
你有听到什么声音吗
Did you hear something?
我不喜欢这个地方
Don't like this place.
整天只能干等
All this hanging about.
瓦格哈尔早该到了
Vhagar was supposed to be here already.
我们得等它来
We have to wait until she comes.
女王可没说要等
The queen didn't say nothing about waiting.
她说“去那里杀了伊蒙德”
She said, come here, kill Aemond.
我可一点都不期待见到瓦格哈尔
I wouldn't be too keen to meet Vhagar.
它和独眼至少杀了两条龙
She and the One-Eye have slain at least two dragons already.
但为了城堡
Fight'll be worth it, though.
这样的战斗是值得的
For the castle.
什么城堡
What castle?
女王答应封我们为骑士
The queen promised to make us knights,
所以我们会获封城堡
so we get a castle.
- 怎么了  - 你必须被任命为领主
- What? - You have to be named a lord
才会获封城堡
to get a castle.
- 那骑士会得到什么  - 一匹马
- What's a knight get, then? - A horse.
我要一匹该死的马做什么  我已经有一条龙了
What do I need with a fucking horse?
你会被封为乌尔夫爵士
- I've got a dragon. - You'd be Ser Ulf,
人们必须对你表示敬意
and men would have to show you respect.
人们得对我恭恭敬敬 是因为我他妈的有只巨龙
Men would have to show me respect 'cause of the big fucking dragon.
头衔又不能当饭吃
I can't live in a title.
也不能当酒喝
Or drink it.
我认为会有女人投怀送抱
I imagine there'd be eager women.
有了城堡 女人要多少有多少
Get more women with a castle.
听话 偷羊贼
我们必须去龙石岛
回家吧
你知道伊耿逃走了吗
Did you know Aegon had fled?
他应该要在这里的
He was meant to be here.
伊蒙德才应该要飞走
It's Aemond who should have flown.
你在害怕
You're frightened.
克里斯顿和加尔温爵士身陷险境
Ser Criston and Ser Gwayne are in great peril.
我只是担心我们的骑士
I fear only for our knights.
伊蒙德应该跟他们一起作战
Aemond should be with them.
伊蒙德也很害怕
Aemond's frightened, too.
他驯服瓦格哈尔之后 便忘了恐惧为何物
After he claimed Vhagar, he forgot what fear was.
但他现在想起来了
But he remembers now.
他很清楚 面对雷妮拉的龙群 他必死无疑
He knows that if he has to face Rhaenyra's dragons, he'll die.
索伦爵士
Ser Soren?
欧尔蒙大人率领海塔尔家的大军前来
Lord Ormund marches here with the Hightower host.
派出你最快的骑士 尽快把这个交给他
Dispatch one of your fastest riders and deliver this to him with haste.
这是国王的指示
These are the king's instructions.
国王的
The king's?
尽快 索伦爵士
With haste, Ser Soren.
马上办 皇后陛下
At once, Your Grace.
艾伦 坐下
Alyn, sit.
我特地留了这瓶
I saved this one.
从伊班岛来的
It's from Ib.
我喝太浪费了
Such luxury is wasted on me.
酒已经开了
I've already broken the wax.
我可没打算
And I am not prepared...
一人独饮
to drink alone.
我忘了他们给它取了什么 古怪难读的名字
I forget the guttural name they have for it.
但我知道粗略翻译过来 意思就是“龙之水”
But I believe a rough interpretation is "dragon water."
也许多喝几次就习惯了
An acquired taste, perhaps.
女王传话来了
The queen has sent word.
我们要从封锁撤走五艘船
We are to pull five ships from the blockade,
顺着黑水河而下 占领君临的港口
sail down the Blackwater, and seize King's Landing's port.
她要占领君临
She's taking King's Landing?
现在雷妮拉占了绝对优势
Rhaenyra's advantage is now absolute.
她会派她的龙包围君临
She will surround the city with her dragons
逼伊耿与伊蒙德投降
and force the surrender of Aegon and Aemond.
我承认我对这个敌人所知甚少
I admit I know little of this enemy.
但独眼伊蒙德似乎是 那种宁可让一切付之一炬
But Aemond One-Eye seems the sort
也不愿放弃王位的人
who would sooner let it all burn than abandon the throne.
前方有惊涛骇浪
Rough seas lie ahead.
我无法完全修复
I cannot fully mend...
我们之间的裂痕
the breach between us.
但我接受这是我的过错
But I do accept that it was of my making.
我很喜欢你母亲
I was fond of your mother.
无论我们当时...
For...
曾拥有过什么
whatever we had together.
我曾试着为你和你哥哥
I did try to provide a life for you.
提供安稳的生活
For your brother.
安稳的生活 或许吧
A life, perhaps.
但从未给过名分
But never a name.
我对此感到抱歉
I am sorry for it.
前方有船
Sail ho!
朝我们过来了
发现敌舰
Enemy ships sighted!
弓箭手前往桅顶就位
径直朝东北方向前进
发现敌舰
Enemy ships sighted.
- 他们有多少兵力  - 目前已清点出53艘
- What is their strength? - Three-and-fifty counted so far.
他们的船数已经超过我们了
They already outnumber us.
放下船桨 派渡鸦去龙石岛报信
Put the oars out. Send ravens to Dragonstone.
放下船桨
Put the oars out!
航向封锁前方 通知舰队形成战线
Take us to the head of the blockade and signal the fleet: form battle lines.
来的是兰尼斯特家 还是葛雷乔伊家的人
Is it the Lannisters or the Greyjoys?
是三女儿王国
It's the Triarchy.
把我的盔甲拿来
Bring my armor.
司令
Commander.
喉道有三个通往黑水河的入口
The Gullet has three inlets into the Blackwater,
其中最大的一个 就在潮头岛的正南方
the largest of which opens just to the south of Driftmark.
但我坚信 我们必须向南方的入口推进
But I hold strongly that we must press towards the southern inlet.
如果我们的舰队 与瓦列利安的舰队短兵相接
If our armada engages the Velaryon fleet at close combat,
就能削弱雷妮拉的龙群的威胁
it will blunt the threat of Rhaenyra's dragons.
他们不会愿意烧毁自己的战舰
They will be loath to burn their own ships.
聪明的策略 大人
A canny strategy, my lord.
难怪你的国王会任命你为海政大臣
I can see why your king made you Lord of the Ships.
如果你最后落海 你会后悔穿成这样
You'll rule all this kit if you wind up in the drink.
我的策略非常明确 就是不要落海
My strategy is expressly not to "end up in the drink."
在我们落海前 会先在甲板上分出胜负
We will face death on this deck before we face it in the sea.
当战斗开始时 你会庆幸有穿盔甲的
You will be glad of our armor when the fighting starts.
我知道我会
I know I will.
海蛇的斥侯发出警报了 司令
The Sea Snake scouts have raised the alarm, Commander.
真想看看他的脸
If only to see his face.
示意哈夫贾率领麾下分队 突破北方隘口
Signal Halfjaw to take his detachment and penetrate the northern pass.
北方隘口在龙石岛北边 是最远的路线
The northern pass is the farthest route
要去那做什么
running north of Dragonstone. Whatever for?
打劫高潮城
To sack High Tide.
科利斯大人的城堡
Lord Corlys' castle?
我们需要你所有舰队的战力 如果要...
We will require the full strength of your fleet if we have any hope--
高潮城是海蛇的大本营
High Tide is a monument to the Sea Snake himself.
当他看到他的藏宝库陷入火海时 还能保持专注吗
Do you think his focus will hold when he sees his treasure room aflame?
大胆琼恩 今日天候如何
What is the weather to be today, Bold Jon?
根据信使那难看的脸色 看来接下来要倒大楣了
Raining piss or shit, from the looks of the messenger.
早安 爵士
Good morrow, ser.
- 有什么消息  - 早安 海塔尔大人
- What news? - Good morrow, my Lord Hightower.
我带来伊蒙德国王的紧急口信
I bring urgent word from King Aemond.
他现在是国王了
King, is he now?
伊蒙德说我们要在这里扎营 等待进一步消息
Aemond says we have to make camp here and await further word.
他三天后就会加入我们
He shall join us in three days' time.
所以伊耿死了
So Aegon's dead, then?
哪个国王当政都一样
One king is as good as another.
带这个弟兄去洗个澡 饱餐一顿 给他安排个像样的营帐
Have this lad bathed and fed. Give him a good tent.
是 爵士
Yes, sire.
也许好天气会持续下去
Mayhaps the weather will hold.
我们会落到这步田地都是我的错
It is my fault we're in this position.
我竭尽全力将伊耿推上王座 但我...
I strove tirelessly to put Aegon on the throne, but I...
我却没能教会他如何治理国家
I failed to prepare him to rule.
他的软弱是他咎由自取
His frailties are his own.
应该由你来统治的
You should have been king.
如果你先出生 也许我们就不会沦落至此 但是...
If you'd only been born first, then perhaps we wouldn't be here, but...
我们只能根据当下的局势做出判断
we must ever play the board before us.
这就是为什么
That is why
你必须去赫伦堡
you need to go to Harrenhal.
去那里做什么
To what end?
那里是要塞
It is a stronghold.
曾经抵挡过龙焰的要塞
One that has withstood dragonfire once before.
你在君临已经不安全了
You are no longer safe here in King's Landing.
害怕是正常的
It is well to be fearful.
我也很害怕
I, too, am afraid.
我不害怕
I'm not afraid.
你当然不怕
Of course not.
但你现在是国王了
But you are the crown now.
雷妮拉会派新的龙来杀你
And Rhaenyra will send her new dragons here for you.
迟早都会
Soon or late.
我不怕
I am not afraid.
飞去河间地
Fly to the Riverlands.
把戴蒙引出来
Draw Daemon out.
他身边只有一只龙 杀了他对雷妮拉会是一大打击
He has just one dragon, and killing him would be a vicious blow to Rhaenyra.
到了赫伦堡 你就无法被攻破了
At Harrenhal, you will be unassailable.
也许我可以在那里跟你碰面
Perhaps I could even meet you there.
飞去那里前路未明
That road is uncertain.
但留在此处
But this one,
如果你留在这里 等雷妮拉和她的龙过来
if you stay here and wait for Rhaenyra
命数就已成定局
and her dragons to come, this one is certain.
你好勇敢
You are so courageous.
但我不能像失去伊耿那样失去你
But I cannot lose you as I did Aegon.
如果我失去你 我将不知所措
If I do, I will be lost.
听我的话 伊蒙德 拜托了
Heed me, Aemond, please.
我会在黑心赫伦的厅堂
I shall host a feast there in your honor.
为你举办一场盛宴
In Black Harren's hall
将我叔叔的首级插在长矛上
whilst my uncle's head looks down from a spike.
要是伊蒙德发现我们要伏击他呢
What if Aemond knew we were coming for him?
他大可趁我们不在时攻击龙石岛
He could have attacked Dragonstone in our absence.
女王指派任务给我们
Queen assigned us a task.
我们必须执行到底
We must man it steadfastly.
如果敌人就指望这个呢
And if that is what the enemy is counting upon?
- 那是什么  - 去他的鬼地方
- What is that? - Fuck this place!
- 怎么回事  - 我要走了 就是这样
- What's happened? - I'm leaving is what's happened.
我们必须等瓦格哈尔
We must wait for Vhagar.
等多久 等到永远吗
For how long? Forever and a day?
它要来早就来了
She was meant to be here already.
女王只指示我们伏击瓦格哈尔
The queen only instructed us to ambush Vhagar.
她没说如果瓦格哈尔没来该怎么办
She did not say what to do if the dragon never came.
我说我们该留下来
I say we remain.
谁他妈让你当国王了
Who made you fucking king?
我不喜欢这里
I don't like it here.
你要这样向女王陛下交代吗
Is that what you'll tell Her Grace?
说你是个懦夫
That you're craven?
我会如实告诉女王陛下
I'll tell Her Grace true.
说我们站岗 瓦格哈尔根本没出现
That we stood watch and Vhagar never came.
你朋友说得没错
Your friend's right.
你们错过战争了
You're missing the battle.
女王需要你们去龙石岛
The queen needs you at Dragonstone.
- 你是谁  - 我是女巫
- Who are you? - I'm a witch.
好了 请多保重
Right. Look after yourselves.
戴蒙离君临还有十天的路程
- 至少他会及时赶到 - 陛下
Your Grace!
- 喉道正在交战 - 跟谁交战
- There is war in the Gullet. - Who?
一支自东方旭日航行而来的舰队
An armada of ships sailing out of the rising sun from the east.
敌人发动埋伏了
They have sprung their trap.
我去看看
I shall go.
母亲
Mother!
停下 你不能去
Stop! You cannot!
你要说的话我都听过了
There is nothing you can say that I have not heard.
如果你死了...
If you die...
那你终于可以当国王了
Then you will at last be king.
拿我的骑乘皮甲来
My riding leathers.
你必须把这扇门闩上并上锁
You are to lock and bar this door.
必须限制女王的行动 直到她恢复理智
The queen must be confined until she regains her senses.
我不能违抗女王陛下的命令
I could not defy Her Grace's commands.
你是女王铁卫的骑士 洛伦特爵士
You are a knight of the Queensguard, Ser Lorent.
你发誓要保护女王陛下 不受任何威胁
You swore to protect Her Grace from all threats.
包括她自己
Including herself.
用你的命...
Your life...
换她的命
for hers.
小杰 快收回成命 这是叛国
Jace. Rescind your command. It is treason.
她拒绝了我的建言 并千方百计阻止我参战
She has rejected my counsel, my every attempt to join the fight.
所以你反而对她宣战
So you make war with her instead?
如果这是另一场伏击行动 就像鸦栖堡战役一样呢
This is all the work of an ambush, like Rook's Rest,
如果这只是引女王过去的诡计呢
a ruse to draw out the queen herself.
他们杀了我弟弟 贝妮拉
They killed my brother, Baela.
我不会让他们也夺走她
I won't let them take her as well.
跟我一起去
Come with me.
我们准备好了
We are ready.
我们可以为她拿下这场胜利
We can win this victory for her.
这不一直都是我们的目标吗
Was this not always our purpose?
洛伦特爵士 开门
Ser Lorent, open the door.
女王陛下 这是杰西里斯王子的命令
Your Grace, it was the Prince Jacaerys' command.
为了确保您的安全
To ensure your safety.
他妈的快开门
Open the fucking door.
我办不到
I cannot.
洛伦特爵士
Ser Lorent!
小杰
Jace!
快给我开门
You open the fucking door!
马上放我出去
You release me at once!
我会让你们人头落地
I will have your heads for this!
弩弓手 预备
Crossbows, ready!
- 放箭 停 放箭 - 弓箭手
Release!
预备
Archers, ready!
放箭
Release!
弓箭手 预备
Archers, ready!
放箭
Release!
瞭望兵 向舰队发出讯号
Barrelman! Signal the fleet:
不要集结
Do not cluster.
- 让他们继续追 - 遵命
Keep them on the chase.
- 交给你们了 - 弓箭手 预备
- Aye-aye! - The fight is yours.
弓箭手
Archers, ready!
- 快  - 放箭
- Archers, go! - Loose!
看到指挥舰了 大人
Flagship's been sighted, m'lord.
- 是悍妇铁拳号 - 洛哈
- It's the Bitchfist. - Lohar?
预备
- 用力推 - 小心
武装起来 朝它逼近 我要让他们看见我们的踪影
Harden up and make towards her. I want her to sight us.
遵命 大人
Aye, m'lord.
武装起来 加快速度
Harden up! Pick up the stroke!
它来了 各位
Here she comes, lads!
不起眼的宝藏船
Our jewel in the rough.
向舰队发出讯号 海蛇由我们对付
Signal the fleet. The Sea Snake belongs to us.
待我们夺下这艘船 战利品大家平分
An equal share of the plunder when we take the ship!
- 是 司令 - 司令
- Aye, Commander! - Commander!
司令
Commander!
我们要对付的是指挥舰
Ours is the flagship.
我们不能只专注在单一目标上
We cannot give ourselves to a singular pursuit.
我们必须带头进攻 以免阵线崩溃
We must lead the assault lest it fall into disorder.
你以为我航行过狭海
Do you think I sailed across the Narrow Sea
是为了替你的国王赢得战争吗
to win your king's war for him?
合约上就是这么写的
Those were the terms of the contract.
20多年来 海蛇带头
The Sea Snake led the persecution and slaughter
迫害并屠杀我的同伴
of my mates for more than 20 years.
我是为了杀他才与你们合作
I sealed your contract for him.
今晚 我们将踏平高潮城
Tonight, we shall walk in the ashes of High Tide!
当我坐上浮木王座 以海蛇之耳为食
You'll all join me as I sit the Driftwood Throne
你们都将与我一同狂欢
and dine on the Sea Snake's ears!
- 解开船绳  - 划桨就位
Break us free!
追上去
And give chase!
他只是想保护你
He wishes only to protect you.
我从未要求他保护我
I never asked to be protected.
我可以预见御前议会的背叛
I expect it from my council,
那些懦弱的家伙 整天只会畏畏缩缩地抓着自己的外衣
those craven men ever clutching at their doublets.
但我的女王铁卫
But my Queensguard?
我的亲生儿子
Mine own son?
或许我有着女人的娇弱身躯
I may appear to have the weak and feeble body of a woman,
但我拥有国王的意志和精神
but I possess the heart and spirit of a king.
右舷有敌人
Enemy to starboard!
- 散开... - 弩炮 重新装填
- Split, split, split! - Ballistae, reload!
把火扑灭
And put those fires out!
舰队被包围了
The fleet is surrounded.
悍妇铁拳号现在派一小支分队 来追我们
And the Bitchfist now pursues us with a small detachment.
- 有龙  - 有龙
- Dragon! - Dragon!
有龙
Dragon!
设定通过龙石岛隘口的航线
Set a course through the Dragonstone Pass.
快要退潮了 我们会搁浅的
The tide is nearly out. We'll run aground.
洛哈只想对付我
Lohar only wants me.
她会跟上来的
She'll follow.
没有她 他们的舰队就无人掌舵
Without her, their fleet will be rudderless...
沦为我们龙群的猎物
and easy prey for our dragons.
- 向右转舵  - 准备战斗 各位
- Starboard on our helm! - Fight ready, men!
把钩索拿来
Bring the grapnels!
- 上 - 前进
- 就位 - 预备
- Ready? - Ready!
船长
净空
装填
Load!
稳住 沃马克斯 冷静
叫我屠龙者洛哈
Call me Lohar, Dragon-Slayer!
继续追击
Press the pursuit!
往上 沃马克斯
继续飞
去吧 月舞 去支援
松开帆索 放下船桨
Ease the sheets and put out the oars.
抛出测深绳
Cast the leadlines.
收帆
Clew up the course.
测深员 前往测深位置
Leadsmen, to the channels.
抛出测深绳
Cast the leadline!
划
水深6?
Depth, six fathoms!
瞭望兵 回报
Barrelman, report!
正前方有碎浪 潮水正急剧退去
Breakers dead ahead. Tide's running hard out.
暗流正强力将我们推向左舷方向
Currents are strong set to larboard.
三艘敌舰从后方快速接近
Three enemy ships closing fast astern!
向左打舵
Larboard your helm.
听好我的指示
Follow my direction closely.
有一条路能通过隘口 但非常狭窄
There is a way through the pass, but it is narrow.
水深5?半 还在急速变浅
Depth: half-five and fast receding!
- 七  - 速度 七节
- Seven! - Speed: seven knots!
稍微向左转舵
Slight to larboard.
是 司令大人
Aye, Lord Admiral.
跟着它的尾浪走
Follow her wake.
我们不能再往前了
We must go no further.
隘口水太浅了
The pass is too shallow.
我们对这个地方一无所知
We do not know the lay of this place.
我们等于是瞎子摸象
We are sailing blind.
跟着海蛇就行
The Sea Snake will guide us.
- 水深4?1呎 - 4?1呎
- One over four! - One over four!
距离大约70码
Perhaps 70 yards' distance.
慢慢来
Easy now.
往右转舵
Starboard your helm.
太多了 轻轻转回来
Too strong. Ease it back.
- 报深度 - 水深4?少2呎
让我来
Let me.
- 水深4?少2呎 - 现在距离剩40码
Forty yards now.
35码
Thirty-five!
- 水深3?半  - 水深3?半
- And a half-three! - And a half-three!
收桨
Bank the oars.
舵手听令 收桨
Coxswain ahoy! Bank oars!
收桨
给他们一点时间
- 25码 - 25码
- Twenty-five yards! - Twenty-five yards!
- 水深3?1呎 - 3?1呎
- One over three! - Ten yards!
- 10码 - 10码
- Ten yards! - We're over the Teeth!
我们通过尖石礁了
安全通过了
We're clear!
让尖石礁解决洛哈
Leave Lohar to the Teeth.
返回喉道 我们必须重新加入战斗
Take us back to the Gullet. We must rejoin the fight.
我们到家了
去吧 偷羊贼
去帮忙
立刻派三个人去右舷
Three hands to starboard, now!
- 派三个人去右舷 - 我们要搁浅了
- Three hands to starboard! - We're going to wreck!
我们直接走进他的陷阱了
We have walked directly into his snare.
两人往左舷 稳住船身
Two hands to larboard now and hold her there!
- 两人到左舷 稳住 - 切断锚
- Two hands to larboard, hold! - Cut the anchors!
减轻重量 减少吃水量 快点
Drop weight and raise our draft. Quickly!
- 是 司令  - 帮帮他们
Aye, Commander!
切断锚
Cut the anchors!
你的盔甲有多重
What do you weigh in that armor?
把其他人也解决了
And the rest of them!
稳住阵脚 把该死的船桨收回来
Hold that line, and pull the fucking oars in!
放下船桨 拉近距离 准备好钩索与缆绳
Oars out and close the distance! Bring the hooks and lines!
敌方指挥舰通过了 它从后方快速接近中
Enemy flagship is clear. She's closing fast astern.
- 快走 快走  - 它的速度比我们快
She has the legs on us. We can't outrun her.
我们甩不掉它 而且目前的风势 也不足以让我们逆流而上
And we've not yet the wind to carry us against the current.
收起船帆 放下船桨 向右急转舵
Furl the sails and put the oars out. Hard round to starboard.
准备发动攻势 进行侧舷猛攻
Ready the offensive for a broadside assault.
所有盾兵和弩弓手 各就各位
All shields and crossbows, to your stations!
装填弩炮
Load the ballistae!
登舰部队
Boarding party!
Boarding party.
用力划 别松懈 抵抗水流
Hard about and keep pulling! Strong against the current.
- 划  - 否则船会被暗流拖回尖石礁
- Turn! - Or she'll be dragged back into the Teeth.
船没有转向
She's not turning!
所有盾兵和弩弓手前往右舷
All shields and crossbows to starboard!
侧舷准备
Broadside, ready!
就位 前进 就位
Positions, move! Positions!
弩弓手准备
Crossbows, ready!
- 预备  - 攻击
- Ready! - Strike!
坚持航向 继续划桨
Hold that course and fucking row!
做好冲击准备 保持戒备
Brace and be ready!
就是现在 攻击
Now, strike!
占领敌舰
Take the ship.
动起来 各就各位
On your feet! Prepare to engage!
诸神啊
把驭龙骑士射下来
Bring down the rider!
不
回避
往上
听话
不...偷羊贼
不
- 不  - 有龙 有龙
他们不是敌人
追上去 月舞
不 偷羊贼
冷静
服从我
攻击
回避
上啊 沃马克斯
保护月舞
不 不 偷羊贼
No! No! Sheepstealer,
不
no!
听话
那是我姐姐
That's my sister.
父亲
Father!
撑住 贝妮拉
Hold on, Baela!
杀了驭龙骑士 沃马克斯
雷妮亚
Rhaena!
不 沃马克斯
转向 转向
不 偷羊贼
Sheepstealer!
不
偷羊贼
Sheepstealer! No!
沃马克斯
Vermax!
小杰
Jace!
往下冲 月舞
快点
小杰
Jace!
飞啊 沃马克斯
Come on, Vermax!
飞啊
待续
谢谢观赏
翻译:郭元箴